原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译       洗七里      油腻希         无伤大雅赛太公
翻译       Effy17      Flora哎呀呀
校对        新浪微博@赛太公
时间轴       三水
后期       瓜瓜
总监       生无可恋瓜
家  庭
摩  登
第十季 第六集
我不记得家里有买新鲜的蜜桃小翘臀啊
I don't remember buying these fresh peaches.
抱歉  瑟奇
Apologies, Serge.
我妻子克莱尔似乎忘记了
My wife, Claire, seems to have forgotten
我在家里办公
that I'm holding office hours
让房地产入门课的学生来学习
for my Intro to Real Estate class here at home.
所以我十分钟前
So, when I walked to the laundry room
只穿着文胸进洗衣房时...
10 minutes ago in my bra...
时机倒是再合适不过了
That was kind of perfect, actually.
我刚给他讲完  七十年代早期的"建筑"
I had just made a point about how buildings from the early '70s
至今仍出人意料地"坚挺"
were holding up surprisingly well.
或许我该...
So maybe I'll...
-是啊  -是啊
- Yeah. - Yeah.
上课时见  伙计
All right, see you in class, buddy.
多好的孩子
‭What a great kid.
这就是我献身学术界的原因  克莱尔
That's why I chucked it all for a life in academia, Claire.
这感觉太特别了
It's a special feeling
知道这世界某处有个年轻人
knowing that there's a young man walking around out there
是你帮忙打造他的品格  能让你骄傲
who you helped mold, who you can be proud of.
-爸  -你懂吗
- Hey, Dad. - Hey. You know?
你起得真早
You're up early.
你这话什么意思
What are you talking about?
刚才我还从背后抱你来着
I hugged you from behind earlier.
我说"我不记得家里有买六块腹肌[啤酒]啊"
You know, I said, "I don't remember buying this six pack."
然后你用很搞笑的东欧口音说
Then you did that funny Eastern European accent --
"我不想惹麻烦
"I don't want trouble.
我只想学习"
I just want to learn."
我们是否该担忧一下集体性骚扰瑟奇的事
Should we be concerned about group-molesting Serge?
而且你不是再少一个学生
And aren't you at the minimum number of students
-课程就会被取消吗  -不必担心
- before they cancel your class? - ‭Not to worry.
瑟奇很崇拜我  班上其余同学也很靠谱
Serge worships me, and the rest of the class is super solid.
再说  过了今天就不准弃课了
Plus, it's the last day to drop classes anyway.
说到弃课
Oh, speaking of that,
我在考虑放弃历史课
I'm thinking about dropping history.
-为什么  -我觉得很无趣
- How come? - It's not really exciting me.
再说  有份大论文今天该交
Plus, we've got this huge paper due today
我的开始动工计划还没结束
that I haven't quite finished starting.
要写门罗主义
It's on the Monroe Doctrine.
门罗主义
The Monroe Doctrine?
糟糕
Oh, no.
大三历史课
Junior year history class,
我写了一份完美的论文
I wrote the perfect paper.
强力的论点  无可挑剔的辅助论证
Strong thesis, impeccable supporting arguments.
我引用了一位白宫侍从的信件
I quoted from the letters of a White House footman
他回忆道  门罗在浴缸中叫他
who recalled Monroe calling to him from the bath,
"博勒加德  把我的马裤给我
"Beauregard, fetch me my breeches.
我想到了一个主义"
We have a doctrine!"
我只得了C
I got a "C."
你认为这成绩合理是吗
Oh, so you agree with that grade, huh?
别把我当小孩哄
Don't patronize me.
俱乐部的饮食变得清淡健康多了
The food at the club has gotten so much lighter and healthier.
好几个人心绞痛连续发作
We had a run of angina attacks,
所以我们不得不重视心脏健康
so we had to go heart-healthy.
我们在同一个周末先后失去了
We said goodbye to our social chairman, Herb,
社交主席贺布和黄油喷泉
and our butter fountain in the same weekend.
我很遗憾
Oh, I'm sorry.
普里契特先生
Hey, Mr. Pritchett.
您随时可以结账了
I'll take this when you're ready.
-谢谢你  玛利亚  -玛利亚
- Thank you, Maria. - ‭Oh, Maria,
很美的名字  所以常被歌唱
that's a beautiful name. That's why it's often sung.
但你不会唱的
But you're not going to --
♪万福玛利亚♪
♪ Ave Maria ♪
谢幕  行了  他们刚允许同性恋进门
And curtain. Okay, they just started letting gays in here.
别让他们后悔
Don't make them regret it.
你或许也该告诉夏罗娜[歌名]
You might also wanna tell Sharona
-不要靠近这张桌子  -没错
- to steer clear of the table. - ‭Yes.
反正我或许也该留着精力
Yeah, well, I should probably save my energy
为今晚的演出做准备
for my performance tonight anyway.
见鬼  歌洛莉亚和我买了票要去看...
Oh, darn. Gloria and I have tickets to, um...
别担心  杰  不用你去看
Don't worry, Jay. It's-it's not for you.
太好了  我还真编不下去了
Oh, good. I didn't know where I was going with that.
今晚是莉莉学校的募捐演出
Tonight is a fundraiser at Lily's school.
我们在为孩子们募捐
We're, you know, raising money for the kids.
歌唱与小品之夜
A night of song and sketch.
所有孩子爸爸都要演出  或者说
All the dads are performing. Well...
大多数爸爸
most of the dads.
为你骄傲  儿子
Proud of you, son.
我也不是彻底的胜利
Ah, it's not a complete victory.
我还是得去看的
I still have to watch it, so...
多谢你请客吃早饭  爸
Thanks for breakfast, Dad.
我喜欢和你们俩共度时光
I love spending time with you two!
我每个月在俱乐部有最低消费
Every month I've gotta burn off a minimum at the club,
而我认识的每个人居然都没空
and literally, everybody else I knew was busy.
这也是为什么我送出的好多生日礼物
That's also why I give a lot of birthday presents
都是俱乐部专卖店买的  马克杯
from the pro-shop. You know, mugs
遮阳帽  上面印着"跟我的推杆说去"
and visors that say "Kiss My Putter,"
"挑逗我  小鸟球"
"Talk Birdie To Me."
都是好产品  双赢
Quality items. Everybody wins.
假如你们不着急的话
So, if you're not rushed,
该去我们的水疗享受一下
you should treat yourself to our spa.
去试试看...
You know, get a couple of, uh...
标准按摩套餐
a couple of standard treatments.
你真慷慨
Oh, well, you're so generous.
我想说  我们圣诞时送你的这件衬衫
Might I say you look very handsome
你穿着十分精神
in that shirt we gave you for Christmas.
这款还有"皇后珊瑚粉"  糟糕
They also make it in "Queen's coral" -- oh, no.
我是不是剧透了你的生日礼物
Did I spoil your birthday?
听起来是的
Sounds like you might.
-什么事这么好笑  -不过是
- What's so funny? - Oh, it's just that
我和学校的一个孩子妈互通电邮
I've been e-mailing this mom at school.
我和她一起做志愿者
We both volunteer together.
-你发电邮  -没什么的  听着
- You-you e-mail? - It's harmless. Listen.
"杰  在天文馆和你说笑很开心
"Hey, Jay, enjoyed laughing around the planetarium with you.
你的笑话能把人笑到天外"
Your jokes were out of this world."
好吧  假如没有什么
Hm, okay. So, if it's so harmless,
歌洛莉亚肯定也知道这位妙语撩骚的女士
I'm sure Gloria knows about this flirty quipstress.
别添油加醋
Don't make something out of this.
我的天
Oh, my God.
所以他才穿了这件衬衫
That's why he's wearing the shirt.
因为它能衬托出你的蓝眼睛
Because it makes your blue eyes pop.
我不会让你们俩八婆把这潭水弄浑
I'm not letting you magpies dirty this up.
"把车停在秋千那
"Park by the swings
好帮你把东西拿进来"
so I can help you carry stuff in."
"把车停在秋千那
"Park by the swings
好帮你把东西拿"进"来"
so I can help you carry stuff in."
你们这是抹黑  我走了
You're sullying this, and I'm leaving!
-向你女朋友带好  -她不是我女朋友
- Okay, well, say "Hi" to your girlfriend. - She's not my girlfriend.
我们俩会配成一组的唯一理由
The only reason we're paired together
就是因为我们的孩子在同一个阅读小组
is because our kids are in the same reading group.
去你们的
Damn it!
我太喜欢我们的"哦哟哟"了
I love when we "Ooh."
以前我们经常这样  后来不了
We used to do that all the time, and then we stopped.
-为什么  -我不知道
- Why? - ‭I don't know.
乔
Joe!
为什么我在垃圾桶里
Why did I find your eye patch
-发现了你的眼罩  -我不知道
- in the garbage? - ‭I don't know.
因为你又去扔了一张停车罚单吗
Were you throwing away another parking ticket?
你必须戴上
Okay, you have to put it on.
为什么  我的弱视已经好了
Why? My lazy eye is fixed.
好啦  有我在呢
Okay, I'm over here,
再坚持一周
and it's only one more week.
你看起来很硬汉
And you look tough,
像个小战神
like a little warlord.
利亚姆的妈妈到了
Oh, that's Liam's mom.
放学见
See you after school.
好的宝贝  不过答应我
Okay, papi, but promise me
你一整天都会乖乖
that you're going to wear the eye patch
-戴眼罩  -我会戴的
- the whole day. ‭- I will.
真不敢相信你不信任我
I can't believe you don't trust me.
两天前
Two days ago,
我抓到你想
I caught you trying to copy
用打印机复印20美元
a $20 bill in the printer.
爸爸说等我能自己赚钱[造钱]的时候
Dad says I get to pick what we watch on TV
我就能决定我们看什么节目
when I start making my own money.
上学去吧
Go to school.
要是你们准备好了
If you guys are ready,
我和胡里奥就开始了
me and Julio will get started.
对了  你们是不是在校园操场遇到的呢
Oh, by any chance, did you guys meet down by the schoolyard?
"我和胡里奥在操场"是保罗·赛门知名歌曲的歌名
-♪ 我 ♪  -别  别  好了
- ♪ Me ♪ - ‭No -- No. Okay.
就是这里
Oh, that's the spot.
现在我想起来为什么我们
Now I'm remembering why we haven't had
蜜月之后就没有一起做过按摩了
a couples massage since our honeymoon.
阿鲁巴[阿鲁巴岛]
Aruba.
那不是我们度蜜月的地方
That's not where we went.
那是他发出的噪音
That's the noise he made.
阿  鲁  巴
Arrruuuubaaaa.
小卡  你能稍微
Cam, could you just...
稍微  嘘
just...shh.
-抱歉  -谢谢
- I'm sorry. - ‭Thank you.
好了  够了  我今天就到这了
Okay, you know what? I'm gonna call it.
-不做了  -怎么了  他太过火了吗
- Mm-hmm. Nope. - What happened? Was he forward?
不是  我只是无法
No, I just can't relax
在你发出那些声音的时候放松下来
with you making these noises.
那我不发出那些声音就放松不下来
Well, I can't relax without making the noises.
所以我要走了  谢谢你  胡里奥
Which is why I'm leaving. Thank you, Julio,
不好意思  我没记住你的名字
and I'm sorry. I-I didn't catch your name.
我叫啊喂吗喂
It's A-weema-weh.
《狮子王》主题曲歌词
祝你们俩好运
Good luck to you both. Okay.
卢克  亲爱的
Oh, Luke! Honey, hi.
你好啊  妈  一切都好吗
Hey, Mom. Everything all right?
当然  我就是想过来看看
Of course. I just felt like making a stop
社区大学的神圣殿堂
by the hallowed halls of community college.
那些封条是怎么回事
What's with the police tape?
有一些兄弟会的人想把
Oh, some frat guys decided
院长的车开到火人节去
to drive the dean's office to Burning Man.
好吧  反正
Okay. Well, anyhoo,
既然来都来了
since we're here,
在你弃掉历史课之前
before you drop that history class,
能不能把我以前的论文交上去呢
could you possibly turn in an old paper of mine?
我想看看别人的评分
I would love to get a second opinion on it.
当然
Sure,
但是你知道你对我提了一个很奇怪的要求
but you know you just did something weird
而我一个问题都没多问吧
and I didn't ask a single follow-up question?
对
Yeah.
你欠我一次这样的请求
You owe me one of those.
你是怎么把以前的论文导进U盘里的
How'd you even get an old paper on a thumb drive?
很容易...
It was easy.
吧
Ish.
那篇久远的论文是老旧的格式
The old paper was on an old format,
但是把几台老机器连接起来
but it was a simple matter
就能很容易地得到
of stringing a couple of old machines together
我需要的东西了
to get what I needed.
好了
All right.
我一直因为完美主义
Yes, I have been accused of having
饱受诟病
a little problem with perfectionism...
♪ 它在运作 ♪
♪ It's working ♪
但是我对于不公也有意见
...but I also have a little problem with injustice,
就像某位美国总统
much as a certain U.S. President had a little problem
对欧洲帝国主义的看法一样  棒
with European Imperialism. Yes!
当然当一个男人这么做的时候  那是教义
Of course when a man does it, it becomes a doctrine.
而当一个女人这样做
and when a woman does it,
她就是歇斯底里
she's hysterical.
我希望你们喜欢数"乌鸦"
I hope you guys like counting "crows".
"一只乌鸦"[第三方契约]
Es-crows, that is.
这已经成了熟悉的声音
It had become a familiar sound --
我的18个投入的学生笑声合一
my 18 devoted students laughing as one.
只是这次有些不对劲
Only something was different this time.
听起来像是17个
It sounded like 17.
难道中间有人动摇了
Could it be that I had a wobbler in my midst?
果然  佩奇·史蒂文斯
Sure enough, Paige Stevens
正在翻阅课程目录
was going through the course catalog.
要是她走了  我的课程就不足最小人数
If I lost her, I'd be below my minimum
这门课就会被停
and lose the class.
为了其他17个追梦者
For the sake of those 17 dreamers,
我别无选择  只能施展我的邓菲魅力
I had no choice but to unleash the Dunphy charm.
-佩奇·史蒂文斯  -到
- Paige Stevens. - ‭Present.
我们已经点过名了  你表现得很好
Oh, we already did that part, and you nailed it.
我昨天晚上读了你的文章
I read your essay last night.
你私下跟谁一起学习了
Whom did you study privately with?
-不好意思你说什么  -别装了  佩奇
- I'm sorry? ‭- Come, now, Paige.
你的见解  你的遣词造句
Your insight, your grasp of the vernacular.
是弗里蒙特吗
W-Was it Freemont?
还是某一位欧洲人
Or perhaps one of the Europeans?
沙尔芬贝格
Scharfenbrugen?
-不是  -当然不
- No.‭ - Oh, of course not.
他过着隐居的生活  多年没有收学生了
He lives as a recluse. He hasn't taken students in years.
我是想表达
I'm simply saying
你天生的直觉
that your raw instincts
可能是1994年允许佣金分割以来
may be the best thing to happen to real estate
房地产界的最强福音
since the allowing of split commissions in 1994.
你不是跟我们说那是
Didn't you tell us it was --
我们就不能有一会儿
Can we for one moment
能不是你的瑟奇个人秀吗
have a break from the Serge show?!
向我保证几年后
Just promise me that in a few short years
当你成为下一个弗莱德·邓纳姆时
when you become the next Fred Dunham,
你会回来看我们
that you'll come visit us?
你真的觉得
Do you really think...
我不是觉得
I don't think.
我知道会
I know.
就是那儿  一点奉承
From there, it was a bit of flattery,
一丝鼓励
a dash of encouragement,
佩奇就回心转意了
and Paige was turned.
让我把我们的明星学员
So, if I could paraphrase
刚才指出的点改述一下
what our star pupil just pointed out,
有时候问题只是要
sometimes it's just a matter
找到愿意买复式住宅的复式傻子
of finding the "Dupe" in "Duplex."
那个声音又出现了
And there it was again,
那动听的音乐
that sweet music --
18个人的欢笑声
18 people laughing.
所有人下周再见
I'll see you all next week.
肯定的
Definitely.
还有  我会在家办公
Oh, and I am holding office hours at my house,
欢迎你们随时来访
so feel free to come by any time.
没问题
Oh, cool.
你...
Oh, you --
佩奇
Uh, Paige.
"佩奇·邓菲夫人"
"Mrs. Paige Dunphy"?
诅咒啊
Curses.
我鼓励地太过了
I'd over-wooed my wobbler.
我们今晚还一起吃晚餐吗
Are we still on for dinner tonight?
当然  我大概能在我外公的俱乐部
Yeah, I can probably get us in
弄到打烊前用餐的座位名额
to the late seating at my grandpa's country club.
你能等到六点半吗
Can you hold off 'ti:30?
其实  我在想
Actually, I thought
也许我可以去你家给你做饭吃
maybe I could come over and cook for you.
太棒了
Awesome.
这不是我最喜欢的班级爸爸吗
Hey, there's my favorite class dad!
你好啊
Oh, hey. ‭Hey.
帮我系下围裙  好吗
Tie my apron, will you?
我的荣幸
My pleasure.
不  不是我的荣幸[舒服]  当然不是
Uh, not my -- not my pleasure, of course.
这听起来太奇怪了
That sounds weird,
而我不是奇怪的人
and I'm not a weird man.
米奇和小卡搅乱了我的心
Mitch and Cam got in my head.
我本来和那个有趣妈妈有一段完全无害的关系
I'd had a perfectly innocent relationship with the fun mom,
结果被他们弄得我老有负罪感
but then they got me feeling all guilty.
突然间我在学校提到的每件事
Suddenly I couldn't mention one thing in that school
听起来都像是双关语
without it sounding like a double entendre.
"睡觉"时间
Nap time?
乐趣"地带"
Fun zone?
盒装[阴部]果汁
Juice box...
我有鲜嫩多汁的番茄呢
I got some nice tomatoes.
好
Oh, yep.
-你是不是弄洒了什么  -没有
- Did you spill something? - ‭Huh? No.
我只是在很用心地做披萨
I'm just working hard on this pizza.
我想我得把这个取下来
Guess I ought to take this off.
天啊  没了戒指感觉像裸体了一样
Boy, feels naked without it.
你有过这种感觉吗  像裸体了一样
You ever feel that way? Naked?
我真心想相信乔有戴着他的眼罩
I really wanted to trust that Joe was wearing his eye patch,
但是自从在垃圾箱里发现眼罩之后
but after finding it in the garbage,
我必须得来确认
I had to make sure.
我不想让他把视力给毁了
I didn't want him to mess up his vision.
我认为在这个国家  视力是一个很重要的问题
I think it's a big problem in this country.
我所到之处  总有眯着眼看的男人
Everywhere I look, there are men with googily eyes.
我们来自拍吧
Let's take a selfie
是给学校期刊拍的
for the school newsletter, so...
所以显出那对蓝眼睛来
Flash those baby blues.
你给我的烤箱[子宫]预热了吗
Did you preheat my oven?
我不是故意的
Not on purpose.
你刚才反应可真不小啊
Well, that was quite a little snitfit back there.
你是想要让我出丑  还是怎么了
Were you trying to embarrass me, or...?
还能有让你更出丑的事吗
Mm, is that even possible?
要赢过在餐厅唱歌
The singing in the restaurants,
或者按摩时为广告的"试音"可不容易啊
your Herbal Essence audition during the massage?
你知道吗  你才是应该羞愧的那个人
You know, you're the one who should be embarrassed.
我的确感到了羞愧  这不正是吵架的原因吗
I am. Isn't that what we're fighting about?
看看你自己  你甚至不敢
Look at you. You can't even put on
在男士换衣间里
your boxer-briefs in a men's locker room
不用遮羞毛巾小短裙就穿上四角裤
without your little terrycloth shame skirt.
这叫做有涵养  小卡
It's called modesty, Cam.
你能把声音放小点儿吗
Can you please just keep your voice down?
好吧  你知道吗  这都是
Yeah, yeah. You know what? Well, it's all
同样的事
part of the same thing.
你知道吗  我一点都不尴尬
You know, I'm not embarrassing.
你就是个无论做什么都会尴尬的人
You're the one that's just embarrassed by everything.
简直是神经病啊
That is crazy --
-感觉这一撞很值得呢  -我很好
- This seems worth it. - ‭I'm fine.
不  你不好  而这影响了我们所有人
No, you're not, and it's affecting all of us.
你总是让我和莉莉闭嘴
You're constantly shushing Lily and me,
责骂我们就因为我们活得大声
scolding us just for living out loud. ‭
我们就不能晚点再说这件事吗
Can we please have this conversation later?
不  不能  因为我会忙着
No, we can't, because I'll be busy
在父亲节目中演出
performing in Fathers' Follies --
另一件因为你太扭捏而不敢做的事
something else you're too self-conscious to do.
你错过了生活  米奇尔
You're missing out on life, Mitchell.
你得不再那么拘束自己
You need to take off your shackles.
让人们看见
Let people see
你是谁
who you are.
我受够了  闪躲的眼神  那些谎言
I've had enough -- the wandering eye, the lies.
我为什么这么紧张  我什么都没做错
Why was I so nervous? I had done nothing wrong.
好吧  我确实有开一些无害的邮件玩笑
Sure, I engaged in some friendly e-mail banter.
我想我意识到了蓝色衣服能衬托我的蓝眼珠
I guess I realized blue shirts make my eyes sparkle.
披萨派对开始前  也许还在停车场
Might have done a few push-ups in the parking lot
做了几个俯卧撑  但那是给所有人看的
before the pizza party, but that's for everybody.
他就是把我当傻瓜
He's trying to make a fool of me.
索尼娅  我得挂了
Sonia, I have to go.
你一整天都到哪里去了
Where have you been all day?
我明白你在暗示什么了  好吧
I see what you're implying. Fine.
她的名字是劳拉  她对我来说什么都不是
Her name is Laura, she means nothing to me,
我把婚戒取掉的唯一原因
and the only reason my wedding ring is off
是我怕戒指丢在她的"面团"里
is 'cause I was afraid I would lose it in her dough.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你到底在说什么
What the hell are you talking about?
几封邮件  完全无害的小玩笑罢了
Couple of e-mails. Harmless stuff.
"把车停在秋千那  好帮你把东西拿进来"
"Park by the swings so I can help you carry stuff in."
你就在担心这些啊
These are what you're worrying about?
这些什么都不是啊
There's nothing there.
是吗  米奇和小卡在暗示
Yeah, Mitch and Cam were implying
我跟她之间有不寻常的事情
there was something weird going on.
怎么可能嘛
That's crazy.
她才35岁  还貌美如花
She's, like, 35 and gorgeous.
就是啊
Exactly.
不过  我想你念邮件时
Although, I don't think you read that e-mail
没念出它本身的语气
the only way it could have been read.
其实是这种语气
I mean, it could've gone,
"把车停在秋千那
"Park by the swings
好帮你把东西拿"进"来"
so I can help you carry stuff in."
听上去她知道你背不好
Sounds like she knows about your bad back.
杰  小撩一下无伤大雅
Jay, there's no harm in a little flirting,
-特别是你  -此话怎讲
- especially you. - What is that supposed to mean?
你是个好人  你体内自带警报系统
You're a good man. You have, like, a built-in alarm system.
不会让你行差踏错
It keeps you in the right path.
那你在学校为什么那样瞪我
Then why did you shoot me that look at school?
我那是在瞪乔
It was meant for Joe.
我担心他没有你那种强烈的道德心
I worry that he doesn't have your strong conscience.
我害怕他遗传了我家的基因
I worry that he has my family genes
我们说谎都不打草稿
where we can lie and lie and lie and lie
而且不会有丝毫愧疚
without feeling one ounce of guilt.
但你平时没对我说谎吧
Y-You don't lie to me, though, do you?
从没有过
Never.
他来了  我猜他一定会进来
Here he is now. I'll bet he comes in here
为自己说谎道歉
and apologizes for lying.
前提是他遗传了你们家的正直基因
Yeah, if he's like one from your family.
但如果他进来  像个没事人一样
But if he walks in here all easy-breezy
假装自己没做错过任何事
pretending that he didn't do anything wrong,
那他就是百分百拉米雷兹家的人
he's 100% Ramirez,
或者这也不是我们真正的姓
or whatever our real name is.
儿子
Hey, buddy.
对不起  行了吗
I'm sorry, okay?!
戴眼罩的事我说谎了
I lied about wearing my eye patch,
那还只是一系列谎言的开始
and that's only the beginning!
我自行车怎么坏的  我说谎了
I lied about how my bike broke.
我从没遛过斯黛拉
I never walk Stella.
我把她拴在跑步机上
I tie her to the treadmill.
我之前放在枕头底下的三颗掉牙
The last three teeth I put under my pillow
其实都是薄荷糖
were Tic-Tacs.
我是个无可救药的男孩
I'm a terrible boy.
太好了
Oh, good.
他跟你一样软弱
He's weak like you.
疯狂爸爸世界
谢谢你  蒂凡尼的爸爸
Thank you, Tiffany's dad!
接下来  请掌声欢迎
And now, please put your hands together
莉莉  哈珀  扎克和丹妮尔的爸爸们
for Lily, Harper, Zack, and Danielle's dads --
"蜜蜂之膝[生意]"组合
The Bees Knees!
爸爸加油
Go, Dad! Woot, woot!
我是观众席里唯一的爸爸
I was the only dad in the audience.
台下坐着的都是女性和孩子  就我一个男人
It was just me and a bunch of women and children.
发生危难时  通常先救妇女和儿童
我感觉自己就像硬挤上救生艇的懦夫
I felt like a coward on a life boat.
小卡说得对  我错过了很多
I mean, Cam was right -- I-I was missing out.
鲍勃  帮我个小忙
Hey, Bob. A quick favor to ask.
如果哈珀不介意
If you don't think Harper would mind,
你能不能把蜜蜂表演服给我穿一下
do you think maybe I could wear the bee costume?
拿去吧  反正我之后还有表演
Take it. I'm in the show later anyways,
在"感恩之父"组合里唱低音部
playing bass with the Grateful Dads.
那就给我吧
Then good, yeah.
天啊  我真为你感到骄傲
Oh, my God. I'm so proud of you!
谢谢  谢谢各位
Thank you. Thank you!
现在请大家安静片刻
And now we'd like to take a moment
我们一起缅怀亲爱的食堂阿姨
to remember our beloved lunch lady,
佩妮·米勒太太
Mrs. Penny Miller.
老天
Oh, my gosh.
你居然这么做了
I can't believe you did that!
-太棒了  -哎呀别夸了
- That was amazing! - Oh, stop it.
不
No!
天啊
Oh, God.
我们还没吸取手套的教训吗
Did we learn nothing from the gloves?!
抱歉  抱歉  抱歉  我来  我来
Sorry, sorry, sorry. I got it. I got it.
我来弄  我来处理
I got it. I got it. I got it.
头盘
For starters,
是用我祖母配方做的意大利饺子
my grandmother's ravioli.
看起来很好吃
It looks amazing.
我房间里存着一些红酒  以备不时之需
I've been saving some occasion wine in my room.
盒子上的葡萄特性一栏写着"妈妈咪呀"
The grape character on the box is saying "Mamma Mia!"
意语的"我的天啊"
所以应该跟意大利料理很搭
so it should go well with Italian.
教授  您好
Hello, Professor.
我...
I, uh...
看来你接受了我提议的"门户开放政策"
I see you took me up on that open-door policy I mentioned.
我不是来问你学习的事
Oh, I'm not here for office hours.
-这是个约会  -毫不意外
- This is a date. ‭- Of course.
我听说披头士乐队的保罗·麦卡尼当红时
I've heard things like this happened to Paul McCartney
也遇到过这种事
at the height of his Beatles fame.
电影讲述有幸福家庭的老帅哥一夜风流后
小三发疯  不断骚扰他全家的故事
典型的《致命诱惑》套路
It was a classic fatal-attraction situation.
我必须做两件事
I had to do two things.
第一  撑过接下来的十分钟
One -- get through the next 10 minutes
拖到弃我课的截止时间过了为止
'til the deadline to drop my class had passed
方法是用诙谐的玩笑转移她的注意力
by distracting her with light banter
和享用她做的托斯卡纳料理  第二
and enjoying her Tuscan cooking, and, two --
《致命诱惑》里的情节
确认下她有没有暴打克莱尔并把她绑了起来
check to see if she had beaten and restrained Claire.
我会不会用力过猛了
I'm not coming on too strongly,
穿这条裙子来约会
am I, with this dress?
不会
Oh. No.
很可爱
Lovely.
我对自己的烹饪很没自信
I'm really nervous about my cooking.
如果一个男人没有吃光
If a guy doesn't eat every bite
我祖母的意大利饺子
of my grandma's ravioli,
我会发疯
I go nuts.
我们当然
Well, we certainly...
不希望有这种事发生
don't want that to happen,
对吧
do we?
话说
Now, uh...
你是哪里人
where are you from?
老家在哪里
Originally.
我猜是意大利
I would say Italy,
但你没有口音
but there's no accent,
所以你肯定不是
so, obviously, that's not the case.
卢克
Luke.
卢克  我关于门罗主义那篇论文有消息了吗
Luke, any word on my Monroe Doctrine paper?
其实  我决定
Oh, actually, I decided
不弃那门课了
not to drop that class,
所以把论文交上去好像不太好
so it didn't feel right turning it in.
不过发生了有趣的事
But something funny did happen.
我在电脑上打开了你写的论文
I had your paper open on my computer.
佩奇看到了  以为是我写的
Paige saw it and thought it was mine.
她做了一些很棒的改动
She made some really good changes.
-改动  -是啊
- Changes? ‭- Yeah, well,
她在几个地方直接切入正题
she cut to the chase in a few places,
把结尾部分做了精简
cleaned up the ending.
她其实是历史专业的学生呢
She's a history major, you know.
-懂了  -妈  我...
- Get it. - ‭Mom, I'm...
跟人家还在晚餐约会中呢
kind of in the middle of a dinner date.
是吗  如果你继续约会
Are you? By now you might be
你们说不定电影已经看一半  或者在玩桌游了
in the middle of a movie or a board game.
毕竟我们都知道她这人有多爱做改变
We all know how obsessed she is with changing things.
去把论文给我拿来  卢克
Go get the paper, Luke.
太好了  你没事
Oh, good, you're okay.
谁说老娘没事了
I'm not that okay.
我对这佩奇可不太感冒
I'm not a fan of this Paige.
-她挺狗胆包天  -所以你知道了
- She's got some nerve. - So you're aware.
我当然知道  我清楚知道她毫不介意
Oh, I'm aware. I'm aware that she has no problem
把自己的贱爪伸向
putting her grubby, little paws all over
不属于她的事物上
something that doesn't belong to her.
-我看出你很不爽  -是的
- I can see you're upset. ‭- I am.
我不爽的原因是因为
I'm upset because I basically took
我把史上最无聊的东西拿来并弄得有趣
the most boring thing in history and made it interesting.
她大摇大摆走过来就当成自己的东西拿走
She thinks she can just come in here and just make it hers.
-做梦吧  -我有点被伤到
- No. - ‭Feels a little hurtful,
但她是我的学生  这事对我影响巨大
but she is my student, and I have a lot at stake here,
能求你把这件事留给我自己处理吗
so can I please just handle this myself?
你没吃到意大利饺也不算亏
You didn't miss much with the ravioli.
真正的好戏是我的海鲈鱼
The showstopper is my branzino.
闻起来好香啊
It smells great.
我们家平常没机会吃到鱼
We don't get to have fish around here.
我爸超讨厌吃鱼
My dad hates it.
这是我们的家传食谱
Well, this one's a family recipe,
如果你不爱吃  我可能就得抛弃你了
so if you don't like it, I'll pretty much have to drop you.
既然如此
Well...
那我们还是
let's not have
不要再说
any of that
任何疯话了
crazy...talk.
离时限还有2分钟
Two minutes to deadline.
我不能让她弃了我的课
I couldn't let her drop my class!
现在
Now
继续
...back...
说你是从哪里来的
... to where you're from.
加州恩西诺
Encino.
靠
Damn it.
妈  别生她气  她只是...
Mom, don't be mad at her. She was just --
没  她真的改良了许多
No, she made it better.
我写这句的时候脑子里想什么呢
What was I thinking with this sentence?
"受人敬仰的大律师的论点
"The esteemed barrister's argument was as layered
充满层次  仿佛他的晚宴后马裤一般"
as the cuffs on his after-dinner breeches"?
这是我第三次提到马裤了
That is the third time I mentioned breeches.
我当年是在闹哪样啊
What was I going through?
-我可以走了吗  -可以
- Can I go now? - Yeah.
等等  宝贝
Oh, wait, honey.
我觉得这姑娘挺好
I like this girl for you.
她值得你请她喝比盒装红酒更好的酒
She deserves better than boxed wine.
海莉有瓶好酒藏在床底下了
Haley keeps a nice bottle under her bed.
你好像很喜欢吃这道菜
You really seemed to like that.
-是的  -我可以再去做一份
- Oh, yeah. - ‭I could make another one,
但需要花一点时间
but it would take a while.
我看看  现在是7点了
Let's see. It's 7:00 now --
谢天谢地啊
Oh, thank God.
佩奇  我们得聊聊
Paige, we have to talk.
我可能无意间发出了让你误会的信号
I-I may have sent some signals I didn't mean to send.
尽管如此  你的一些举动
Nonetheless, some of your behavior
老实说  稍微有点不太合适
has been a little inappropriate, frankly,
而且也对我妻子有点不敬
kind of disrespectful to my wife.
等等  别急  别说下去
Oh, wait, hang on. Hang on.
这件事我其实改变心意了
I changed my mind about that.
我不生你气
I am not mad at you.
你所做的事只不过是对
All you did was take an interest in something
我25年前就该丢弃的一件事物起了兴趣
that I should have dropped 25 years ago.
-克莱尔  -我能跑题一下吗
- Um, Claire. - And can I say something else?
我十分支持你们交往
I'm all in favor of this relationship.
-克莱尔  -我不想话说太早带来坏运
- Claire? - ‭I don't want to jinx it,
但我觉得你可能真的是他的真命天女
but I think you could be exactly what he needs.
我懂  虽然他看起来像个男人
I know, he may look like a man,
但老实说  在很多方面
but, honestly, in a lot of ways,
他还只是个小男孩
he's still just a little boy.
"房"里的事只能用一团乱来形容
Complete mess in the bedroom.
不过我可以给你个小秘诀
Although, here's a tip for you.
如果你能"驾驭"在他之上  他表现会变好
He actually does respond well if you stay on top of him.
-所以你不介意我跟...  -完全不介意
- So, you're okay with... - Absolutely.
如同某位美国早年前总统说过的
As a certain U.S. President once said,
"让感觉良好的年代开始吧"
"Let the era of good feelings commence."
天啊  这真是我最开心的一天了
Oh, my God! This is the best day ever!
原来佩奇给我做晚餐
So, it turns out Paige was only making dinner for me
纯粹是因为想接近我爸
so she could get close to my dad.
抱歉了  小兄弟  但我警告过大家
I am sorry, buddy, but I did warn everyone
我强大的邓菲魅力了
about the Dunphy charm.
另一件有趣的事情是
It's also a little interesting
佩奇的房产中介父亲在她12岁时
that Paige's Realtor dad abandoned the family
-抛妻弃女跑了  -感觉没关联啊
- when she was 12. - Seems irrelevant.
他也对魔术有过涉猎
He also dabbled in magic.
感觉我们现在完全是在聊两个不同的话题啊
Now we're just having two separate conversations.
你知道她前3任男友都是50岁以上人士吗
Did you know her last three boyfriends were 50?
我劝你还是少花时间去读
Maybe spend a little less time with your nose
你那些心理学的书  多花点时间变性感吧
in that psych book and a little more time being sexy.
等你写完作业了才还给你
You will get this back when your homework is done.
乔  这是什么
Joe, what is this?
我朋友汉娜给我的纸条
Just the notes from my friend Hannah.
朋友吗  我感觉可不是这么一回事
Friend? This doesn't sound to me like that.
这些字条很挑逗呢
This is very flirty.
让我看看
Let me see that.
"亲爱的乔  你想跟我分着吃水果软糖卷吗"
"Dear Joe, wanna share a half of my fruit roll-ups?"
这只是小孩子的童言童语嘛
This is just kids being kids.
好傻好天真
Don't be a fool.
"亲爱的乔  你想跟我
"Dear Joe, wanna share a half
分着吃水果软糖卷吗"
of my fruit roll-ups?"
你这角度看确实不一样
That's a different spin on it.
你这性感声线以前都躲哪了
Where's that voice been?
念念这条
Done this one.
"下课时间一起跑来跑去好好玩啊"
"It was so fun running at recess."
"兰迪的疹子真的好恶心啊"
"Randy's rash is really gross."
或许我们该上楼"谈谈"
Maybe we should go upstairs.
看你的电影吧  乔
Watch your movie, Joe.